# KISHOR CHANDRA TRIPATHY

kctripathy@gmail.com | +91 99380 46866 101-A, Keerthi Rendezvous, KR Puram, Bangalore

#### **IOB SUMMARY:**

Since more than over two decades, my knowledge and skills has been utilizing for requirement analysis, design, develop, test and document many enterprise level web and windows application using Microsoft Technologies.

8+ years of experience as a full stack developer using the technologies like C#.Net, VB.Net, MVC, WebAPI, WCF, Entity Framework, Angular JS, JQuery, Bootstrap, CSS, SQL Server, Oracle and TFS using PMI Methodologies

#### SKILLS

C#.Net, ASP.NET, WebAPI, WCF, MVC, Angular JS, JQuery, SQL Server, Entity Framework, VB6, ASP and FoxPro

# **EXPERIENCE**

July 2016 - Till Date : **IT Consultant** (Freelance) for TSD College, Odisha, 761120 ~ <a href="http://www.tsdcollege.in">http://www.tsdcollege.in</a> Jun 2015 - Jun 2016 : **IT Manager** for Kcal Group, JLT, Dubai (UAE) ~ <a href="http://www.kcallife.com">http://www.kcallife.com</a>, <a href="http://www.kcallife.com">kcalextra.com</a>

Oct 2010 - May 2015: IT Consultant (Freelance) for Ortel Communications Ltd., Odisha TV and MBC TV

May 2006 - Sep 2010 : Module Lead for CMA CGM Systems, Media City, Dubai (UAE) ~ http://www.cma-cgm.com

Aug 2003 - May 2006: Software Engineer for Mindfire Solutions, Bhubaneswar, Odisha, 751010

Aug 1997 - July 2003: Faculty cum Programmer, Macaw Consultancy Services/NICE, Balangir, Odisha, 767001

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- ✓ Recently I successfully gathered requirement for a NAAC Accredited college (<a href="http://www.tsdcollege.in">http://www.tsdcollege.in</a>), managed the complete project and delivered the Educational ERP project (Integrated Campus Automation System) in due frame of scope, time, cost and quality while managing and mitigating all the risks of the project.
- Successfully Managed the development of customized ERP software to cater the MBC TV's business need
  - o Analyzed the project requirement and created the work breakdown structure to assign it to the team members
  - o Identified all the risks and mitigated it with the help of the team and senior management
  - O Managed all the stakeholders expectations and resolved the conflicts among few team members
  - Developed the schedule plan using MS Project 2010 software and executed the project accordingly
- ✓ During 2006-2010, while working for CMG CGM Systems in Dubai, I successfully captured the knowledge of three projects developed by FWL Technologies, Liverpool, UK in Visual Basic 6.0 within a given time frame of twenty one days and was maintaining the projects independently. Ported the same .Net Framework using Visual Studio 2010
- ✓ While working as a freelance consultant for Micro Group/MBC TV, I successfully set up their environment by deploying a Domain Controller and attached all the PCs to the DC, Installed and set up the SQL Server 2008R2 & Team Foundation Server. With the help of a team, I developed a customized ERP application using C#.Net, deployed it in around 50 branches of the company after providing in-house training to the trainers of the client.
- ✓ While working for Ortel, I successfully developed some software to gather all the data consumed by their customers (cable modem users) in a Oracle database and developed an website as <a href="http://www.cm.ortel.net">http://www.cm.ortel.net</a> to display to the users.
- ✓ Successfully automated the transmission system of the Odisha TV (OTV) using Visual Basic6 and SQL Server

## **QUALIFICATIONS**

1990-1993 : B.Sc., Passed with 1st class and honours from Berhampur University, Ganjam, Odisha 1995-1997 : Honours Diploma in System Management from NIIT Ltd., Bhubaneswar, Odisha

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- ✓ Completed 40 hours of PMP Training and now preparing to appear for Certification
- ✓ Certificate in MS Project 2007 from NADIA Training Institute, Dubai in 2009
- ✓ Certificate in Oracle and Visual Basic6 from SSI Ltd, Bhubaneswar, Odisha in 2000
- ✓ Certificate in Computing from IGNOU, Bhubaneswar, Odisha in 1999

#### **SOME OF THE PROJECTS**

Project: INTEGRATED CAMPUS AUTOMATION SYSTEM (ICAS)

Client : <u>Tentulia Sasan Debasthan College</u>, BD Pur, Ganjam, Odisha 761120

Duration : 13 months (July 2016 to August 2017)

Technologies : .Net 4.5, C#, ASP.NET, MVC, WebAPI, EF, SQL Server, Angular S and Bootstrap

Software / Tools : MS Visual Studio.Net 2013, Team Foundation Server 2010, MS SQL Server 2008, MS Visio 2010,

MS Project 2007, MS Office 2010 & WBS Pro2.7

Role : Full Stack developer. It includes managing the project using PMI Methodology or from initiation

to closure phase, designing the graphics, providing training and mentoring team.

## **Project Description:**

The need for having this project is to record and manage all the day-to-day activities of the College. The software is a bundle of windows and web application. Web application is responsive, which has the modules like Administration, Establishment, Students, Staffs, Finance & Library Management. Users, Roles, permission, menu items, common dropdown values, etc. are being managed by Administration module, Students admission, transfer, leaving, attendance, examination has been taken care under student module. Staff's publication, attendance, salary, payments, exam mark entry, etc. has been managed under staff module, Notice, Tenders, Circulars can be managed under Establishment module.

We have also delivered one windows application which reads an excel sheet as downloaded from the Department of Higher Education website and insert into the college website.

Project : MICRO DATA CENTRALISATION SYSTEM (IN-HOUSE ERP APPLICATION)

Client : Micro Leasing and Funding Limited, Bhubaneswar

Duration : 50 months (Oct 2010 to Dec 2014)
Technologies : .Net 3.5, C#, ASP.NET, SQL Server and

Software / Tools : MS Visual Studio.Net 2013, Team Foundation Server 2010, MS SQL Server 2008, MS Visio 2010,

MS Project 2007, MS Office 2010 & WBS Pro2.7

Role : Accountable to deliver the software using PMI methodology and managing a team of 12 guys.

# **Project Description:**

The project has developed for a finance company, which has around 50 branches across all the districts in Odisha. The software is basically records all the day to day transactions of the company and was recording it into a centralized database located in their head office. It was also helpful for the Human resource department by managing the payroll, leaves, deductions, advances etc. The software has a field force module, which manages the Agents, field officers and their chain along with calculation of commissions and incentives. It was also helpful for the top management to take decisions after getting several reports like which branch have generated how much revenue in a financial year. It was also taking care of the month end process and year end process of the company.

Project : IN-HOUSE SOFTWARE FOR KCAL BUSINESS MANAGEMENT

Client : Kcal Group, Jumeirah Lake Towers, Dubai (UAE)

Duration : 11 months (June 2015 to May 2016)

Technologies : C#.Net, ASP.NET, MVC, WebAPI, SOL Server, CSS, Windows Services and TFS

Software / Tools : MS Visual Studio.Net 2010, Team Foundation Server 2010, MS SQL Server 2008, Crystal Report

2010, MS Visio 2010, MS Project 2007, MS Office 2010 & WBS Pro2.7

Role : Analysing the Requirement, Architecting the application, Managing the scope, time and cost of

the project. Involved in coding and code review, providing in house training to client

## **Project Description:**

This is also a bundle of web and windows applications to manage their customers more efficiently. Basically, we have developed a web application (<a href="http://www.kcalextra.com">http://www.kcalextra.com</a>) for the public to register themselves which records to a MySQL database hosted in a rented server. One windows service, we have created which was reading the above database every five minutes and was fetching the newly registered records and was inserting into an SQL Server database located in their office. One windows application has been developed for the customer relationship executives, who can see the record of the people, who has registered in their website. They were communicating with that person to make a diet plan using the developed software. The chef in kitchen could able to prepare the recipe for the customers on daily basis. The packaging department were able to know what to pack for every customer. The Logistics department then were dispatching the packed food to the respective customer. Finance department were using the software to record the financial transaction, generate the ledgers and getting the balance sheet.

Project Name : HAZARDOUS CARGO APPROVAL AND REQUEST PROPOSAL (HARP)

Front End : Visual Basic6, Visual Basic.Net 2005

Client : CMA-CGM Group, Marseille, France

Back End Tool : Oracle 10g R2

Role : Interacting with business analyst for requirements, understanding the functional

specification, breaking down it into activities, coding and delivering after reviewing the code.

#### **Project Description:**

Hazardous goods transportation must be carried out in accordance with IMDG (International Maritime Dangerous Good) code, US CFR (Code of Federal Regulations) 49 and more generally with safety and security rules according to good practices of the industry. In this context, CMA-CGM guarantees to their customers that these rules and other own extra CMA-CGM restrictions are applied in order to secure transportation. To carry out this aim we developed this software which allow to apply the international/national and local rules in our documentation process.

It is the HARP project or Hazardous Approval Request Process. A real time application being used by the shipping agents across the world to get an approval of the hazardous cargo before it is loaded to the vessel. This application is looking after the nature of the dangerous goods as per the amendments implemented by IMO (International Maritime Organization, a statutory body of UNO). The amendments consists of restrictions to be followed before shipping the good and the segregation rules of different hazardous materials loaded in a same or different containers in a ship.

Project Name : **COMPUTER TRAINING SYSTEMS (CTS)** 

Client : USA Client for Mindfire Solutions

Web Application URL : http://training.ctsys.com/ | http://www.ctsys.com

Tools used for Front End : Macromedia Flash MX 2004 Professional, Action Scipt2.0, Adobe Photoshop 6.0

Tools used for Middle Tier : ASP.Net (Visual Basic.Net 2003) and Flash Remoting

Tool used for Back End : SOL Server 2000

My Role : Interacting with client for requirement gathering, coding and Mentoring the team on

Macromedia Flash Action Script

#### Description:

Computer Training Systems (CTS) is a Computer Based Training (CBT) that has been providing computer-based aviation training to the pilots of United States and is approved by and used by the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA).

It has two modules. First is for pilots/end users and another is for the administrator/owner of the software. With extensive record-keeping and an easy to use course administrator, the training employs three proven training techniques to teach three major elements, general aviation subjects, specific aircraft training and training based on our customers' operation specifications and procedures. The techniques used include tutorials, lessons and examination. Lessons employ extensive use of questions and allow the pilot exciting interaction in an absolutely non-threatening environment. At the end, Users need to appear for exam. The questions are generated randomly and it evaluates the marks obtained by user to let him qualify or disqualify for the certification

# **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Date of Birth: 20th July, 1973Passport Number: J3463726Nationality: IndianReligion: HinduGender: MaleMarital Status: Married

Languages Known : English, Hindi and Odia

Hobbies : Reading, Listening Classical Music, Playing Flute, Keyboard and Harmonium

## **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the information given in this resume is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

# (KISHOR CHANDRA TRIPATHY)